let's see a visual proof of an
interesting inequality using the unit
circle in the cartisian plane label the
origin o start with a radius of length
one and draw a unit circle centered at o
like this let's label the point on the
xais by a imagine a point p on the unit
circle in the first quadrant
corresponding to rotating an angle of T
if we drop a perpendicular from P to the
x-axis and label the intersection Point
M then the length of the line p m is the
S of T by the definition of s now use
the line pm to generate a circle
centered at M with radius s of T call
the intersection point of that Circle in
the x-axis B and label the other
intersection point between the two
circles Q notice that the point Q lies
directly below the point P so that
they're
antipaladin segment O M plus the length
of the line segment MP is equal to the
length of the line segment o and this is
greater than or equal to the length of
the line segment O A from these facts we
can see that the arc length of the Ark
pbq is greater than or equal to the arc
length of the Ark P AQ and that in turn
is greater than or equal to the length
of the chord PQ by construction the ark
pbq is the semicircle of a circle with
radius sin T and therefore has a length
of Pi * sin T The Arc P AQ is 2 two
copies of the Ark PA a subtending the
angle T and therefore the ark PA a q has
a length of 2 T and finally the length
of the chord PQ is equal to 2 * the
length of the line p m which is s of T
and therefore the chord length PQ is 2 *
the S of T from this argument we see
that Pi of s of T is greater than or
equal to 2T which is greater than or
equal to 2 * the S of T from the latter
inequality we see that 2 * the S of T is
less or equal to 2 T so that s of T is
less than or equal to T from the first
inequality we see that 2 * T is less
than or equal Tok * the S of T so that
2T / piun is less than or equal to S of
T when we glue these two together we see
that 2T over Pi is less than or equal to
S of T Which is less than or equal to T
notice this is only true if the angle T
is in the first quadrant so if T lies
between 0 and < / 2 this inequality is
known as Jordan's inequality thanks for
watching if you liked this video check
out my playlist on other mathematical
inequalities and consider subscribing to
the channel